SCOPE OF SERVICES 

The CONTRACTOR shall perform targeted street-based homeless outreach and 
provide support services independent or in collaboration with the San Diego County 
Sheriffs Department, Lemon Grove Substation to the City of Lemon Grove.

In collaboration shall mean that the CONTRACTOR, Home Start, Inc. will partner with 
the San Diego County Sheriffs Department, Lemon Grove Substation to form a four- 
person team comprised of two homeless outreach specialists and two deputies that will 
assist individuals experiencing homelessness by providing emergency hygiene kits and 
food packs, providing transportation to a shelter or medical agency, and/or facilitating 
support services. Independent shall mean that Home Start, Inc. will provide homeless 
outreach without the collaboration to assist individuals experiencing homelessness by 
providing emergency hygiene kits and food packs, providing transportation to a shelter 
or medical agency, and/or facilitating support services.

The CITY shall provide the CONTRACTOR emergency hygiene kits and food packs to 
distribute to individuals experiencing homelessness. Distribution of Emergency hygiene 
kits shall include, but will not be limited to, the following items: face coverings, gloves, 
sanitizes, soap, shampoo, toothbrush and toothpaste, socks, and a razor and shaving 
cream. Distribution of food packs can include, but will not be limited to, the following 
items: water, juice boxes, fruit snacks, crackers, pudding cups, and cookie bags.

The CONTRACTOR shall coordinate transportation to a shelter or hospital for 
individuals that require this assistance.

The CONTRACTOR shall provide the CITY a synopsis associated with the homeless 
outreach and support services that are provided on a monthly basis or when requested.

The CONTRACTOR shall continue to perform homeless outreach and support services 
until all funds have been exhausted or January 20, 2022, whichever date comes first.

The CITY will provide compensation and payment to the CONTRACTOR for the costs 
associated with the performance of the services that are outlined below.

 Budget Item                  Rate      Hours  Worked/   Total Costs
                                        Quantity 
 Homeless Outreach Specialist $28.13    122              $3,431.86
 (including Indirect Costs)
 Homeless Outreach Specialist $28.13    122              $3,431.86
 (including Indirect Costs)

 Ride  Share  To  Shelter for $20       60               $1,200
 Homeless
                                                         $8,063.72



                                     12

             LEASE AGREEMENT BETWEEN 
        THE CITY OF LEMON GROVE AND HOME START 
      FOR PARTIAL USE OF OFFICE SPACE AT CITY HALL

Basic Provisions.
1.1 Parties: This Lease ("Lease") is made by and between the City of Lemon Grove
    ("Lessor") and Home Start ("Lessee"), (collectively, the "Parties", or individually, 
    "Party").

    1.1.1 Premises: An office space located at the building known as the City of 
        Lemon Grove City Hall located at 3232 Main Street, LeMon Grove, CA, 
        91945, consisting of approximately 181 square feet ("Office") as shown in 
        Attachment "A". Lessee shall not have any rights to the building or 
        furnishings. Common areas shown in Attachment "A" also include the copy 
        room, restrooms, and the kitchen/break area.
                 rnar-r
1.2 Term: Commencing on April._ l9 , 2020, the term of the Lease shall be month-
    to-month, as mutually agreed to by both parties. There shall be no holdover 
    tenancy and any changes shall be subject to a written approval by both parties.

1.3 Base Rent: There is no cost to the Lessee. If that changes at any time in the
    future, both parties will mutually agree to establish a cost per month ("Base Rent"), 
    payable on the 1st day of each proceeding month. Any payments not received by 
    the 10th day of each month will incur a 10 percent late fee penalty.

    1.3.1 If a Base Rent is established, an initial deposit will also be mutually agreed 
        upon with the deposit due the next first day of the month-to-month lease.

    1.3.2 Annual Rent Increase: Once established, the annual base rent may 
        increase on July 1st each year based on the increase in the Consumer Price 
        Index for All Urban Consumers (CPI-U) in the San Diego Area or 2.5 
        percent, which ever percent is greater at the discretion of the City Manager. 
        The Lessor has the option to defer any annual rent increase each fiscal 
        year.

1.4 Utilities and Premises Maintenance Costs, San Diego Gas & Electric, Helix Water
    District, telephone, intemet and EDCO solid waste costs will be paid for by the 
    Lessor,

    1.4.1 If a Base Rent is established, each July 1st, costs for utilities and 
        maintenance will be evaluated by the Lessor to determine if a future cost 
        sharing agreement is necessary.

1.5. Agreed Use: Lessee intends to use the Premises to operate as a satellite location 
    to coordinate homeless outreach, schedule field visits, provide services during field 
    visits, and related coordination activities.

    1.5.1 The Lessee is authorized to use the conference room (known as 
        Conference Room A) when not programmed for use by the City and only 
        for professional meetings.

        1.5.2 Any activity not li6ted as an agreed use, must be reviewed and approved 
            in writing by the Lessor at least thirty (30) calendar days before its 
           occurrence.

2.  Premises.
    2.1 Lessor hereby leases to Lessee, and Lessee hereby leases from Lessor, the
        Premises, for the Term of the lease, and upon all of the terms, covenants and 
        conditions set forth in this Lease.

    2.2 Lessee shall not assign, mortgage, pledge, hypothecate, encumber, permit any
        lien to attach to, or otherwise transfer, this Lease or any interest hereunder, permit 
        any assignment or other such foregoing transfer of this Lease or any interest 
        hereunder by operation of law, sublet the Premises or any part thereof, or permit 
        the use of the Premises by any persons other than Lessee and its employees.

    2.3 Lessor shall deliver the Premises to Lessee an office space that is clean and free
        of debris on the Start Date and warrants that the existing electrical, plumbing, and 
        lighting, shall be in good operating condition on said date. If a noncompliance with 
        such warranty exists as of the Start Date, or if one of such systems or elements 
        should malfunction or fail within the appropriate warranty period, Lessor shall, as 
        Lessors sole obligation with respect to such matter, except as otherwise provided 
        in this Lease, promptly after receipt of written notice from Lessee setting forth with 
        specificity the nature and extent of such noncompliance, malfunction or failure, 
        rectify same at Lessor's expense.

    2.4 Lessee shall be entitled to use any publicly available parking space in the City Hall
        Parking lot or on a public street. Said parking spaces shall be used for parking by 
        vehicles no larger than full-size passenger automobiles or pickup trucks, herein 
        called "Permitted Size Vehicles."

        2.4.1 Lessee shall not permit or allow any vehicles that belong to or are controlled 
           by Lessee or Lessee's employees, suppliers, shippers, customers, 
           contractors or invitees to be loaded, unloaded, or parked in areas other 
           than those designated by Lessor for such activities.

        2.4.2 Lessee shall not service or store any vehicles in the parking spaces.

3.  Possession.
    3.1 Lessee Compliance. Lessor shall not be required to tender possession of the
        Premises to Lessee until Lessee complies with its obligation to provide evidence 
        of insurance and secures a business license from the City of Lemon Grove. 
        Pending delivery of such evidence of insurance and approved business license, 
        Lessee shall be required to perform all of its obligations under this Lease from and 
        after the Start Date, including the payment of Rent, notwithstanding Lessor's 
        election to withhold possession-pending receipt of such evidence of insurance. 
        Further, if Lessee is required to perform any other conditions prior to or concurrent 
        with the Start Date, the Term shall commence, but Lessor may elect to withhold 
        possession until such conditions are satisfied, in Lessor's sole discretion.




                                                -2-

4.  Agreed Use.
The Premises shall be used and occupied only for said Agreed Use as defined in Paragraph 1.5 
of this Lease. Furthermore, the premises will remain clean and trash free at the conclusion of 
each use by the Lessee.

6.  Insurance Risks/Security
    6.1 Indemnity. Lessee shall indemnify and hold harmless the City and its officers,
        agents and employees against all claims for damages to persons or property 
        arising out of the conduct of the Lessee or its employees, agents, or others in 
        connection with its use and occupation of the Premises under this Agreement, 
        except only for those claims arising from the negligence or willful misconduct of 
        the City, its officers, agents, or employees. Lessee's indemnification shall include 
        any and all costs, expenses, attorneys' fees and liability incurred by the City, its 
        officers, agents, or employees in defending against such claims, whether the same 
        to proceed to judgment or not. Lessee at its own expense shall, upon written 
        request by the City, defend any such suit or action brought against the City, its 
        officers, agents, or employees. Lessor shall hold Lessee harmless from claims 
        arising from Lessor's sole active negligence or sole willful misconduct or that of its 
        officers, agents or employees.

    6.2 Insurance.

        6,2.1 Lessee shall, throughout the duration of this Agreement, maintain 
            comprehensive general liability or commercial general liability insurance 
            and property damage insurance covering all operations and activities of 
            Lessee, its agents and employees, performed in connection with this 
            Agreement including but not limited to, its personal property, the interior 
            improvements of the PREMISES and automobile coverage. Lessee shall 
            obtain and maintain fire, extended coverage, and vandalism insurance 
            policy(s) on all insurable property on the PREMISES, including the 
            PREMISES.

        6.2.2 Lessee shall maintain the following minimum limits:

            General Liability 
            Combined Single Limit
            Per Occurrence    $1,000,000
            General Aggregate $2,000,000


        6.2.3 All insurance companies affording coverage to the Lessee shall be required 
            to add the City of Lemon Grove as an 'additional insured" under the 
            insurance policy(s) required in accordance with this Agreement.

        6.2.4 All insurance companies affording coverage to the Lessee shall be 
            insurance organizations authorized by the Insurance Commissioner of the 
            State Department of Insurance to transact the business of insurance in the 
            State of California.





                                                      -3-

       6.2.5 Lessee shall provide a thirty (30) day written notice to the City of Lemon 
           Grove should any insurance policy be canceled before the expiration date. 
           For the purposes of this notice requirement, any material change in any 
           policy prior to the expiration shall be considered a cancellation. 
           Cancellation of any coverage required by the terms hereof shall be grounds 
           for termination of this Lease pursuant to the provisions of section 6.2.9 
           hereof.

       6.2.6 Lessee shall provide evidence of compliance with the insurance 
           requirements listed above by providing a certificate of insurance, and 
           endorsements thereon, in a form satisfactory to the City Attorney 
           concurrently with the submittal of this Agreement.

       6.2.7 Lessee shall provide a substitute certificate of insurance no later than thirty 
           (30) days prior to the policy expiration date. Failure by the Lessee to 
           provide such a substitution and extend the policy expiration date shall be 
           considered a default by Lessee and subject the Lessee to a termination of 
           this Agreement.

       6.2.8 Maintenance of insurance by the Lessee as specified in this Agreement 
           shall in no way be interpreted as relieving the Lessee of any responsibility 
           whatever and the Lessee may carry, at its own expense, such additional 
           insurance as it deems necessary.

       6.2.9 If Lessee fails or refuses to procure and maintain the required insurance, 
           or falls to provide the proof of coverage, Lessor, has the right but not the 
           obligation, to obtain the insurance. Lessee shall reimburse Lessor for the 
           premiums paid with interest at the maximum allowable legal rate then in 
           effect in California. Lessor shall give notice of the payment of premiums 
           within thirty (30) days of payment stating the amount paid, names of the 
           insurer(s) and rate of interest. Said reimbursement and interest shall be 
           paid by Lessee on the first (1st) day of the month following the notice of 
           Payment by the Lessor. Notwithstanding the preceding provisions of this 
           Subsection, any failure or refusal by Lessee to procure or maintain 
           insurance as required In this Agreement, or failure to provide proof of 
           Insurance, shall be deemed a default under this Agreement.

       6.2.10 Lessee may choose to satisfy the insurance obligations identified in this 
           Lease through a self-insurance program or a self-insurance joint powers 
           agency or agreement

7   Attorney's Fees.
If any Party brings an action or proceeding involving the Premises whether founded in tort, 
contract, or equity, or to declare rights hereunder, the Prevailing Party (as hereafter defined) in 
any such proceeding, action, or appeal thereon, shall be entitled to reasonable attorneys' fees. 
Such fees may be awarded in the same suit or recovered in a separate suit, whether or not such 
action or proceeding is pursued to decision or judgment. The "Prevailing Party" shall include, 
without limitation, a Party who substantially obtains or defeats the relief sought as the case may 
be, whether by compromise, settlement, judgment, or the abandonment by the other Party of its 
claim or defense. The attorneys' fees award shall not be computed in accordance with any court



                                            -4-

fee schedule but shall be such as to fully reimburse all attorneys' fees reasonably incurred. In 
addition, Lessor shall be entitled to attorneys' feis, costs and expenses incurred in the 
preparation and service of notices of Default and consultations in connection therewith, whether 
or not a legal action is subsequently commenced in connection with such Default or resulting 
Breach ($200 is a reasonable minimum per occurrence for such services and consultation).

8  Dispute Resolution.
   8.1 Mediation: Lessor, Lessee, and Broker(s) agree to mediate any dispute or daim
   arising between them out of this agreement or any resulting transaction, before resorting 
   to arbitration or court action. Paragraphs (2) and (3) below apply whether or not the 
   arbitration provision is initiated. Mediation fees, if any, shall be divided equally among the 
   parties involved. If, for any dispute or claim to which this paragraph applies, any party 
   commences an action without first attempting to resolve the matter through mediation, or 
   refuses to mediate after a request has been made, then that party shall not be entitled to 
   recover any attorney fees, even if they would otherwise be available to that party In any 
   such action. This mediation provision applies whether or not the arbitration provision is 
   initiated.

   8.2 Arbitration Disputes: (1) Lessee and Lessor agree that any dispute or claim in Law
   or equity arising between them out of this agreement or any resulting transaction, which 
   is not settled through meditation, shall be decided by neutral, binding arbitration, including 
   and subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) below. The arbitrator shall be a retired judge or 
   justice, or an attorney with at least 5 years of real estate transactional law experience, 
   unless the parties mutually agree to a different arbitrator, who shall render an award in 
   accordance with substantive California Law. In all other respects, the arbitration 
   conducted in accordance with Part III; Title 9 of the California Code of Civil Procedure. 
   Judgment upon the award of the arbitrator(s) may be entered in any court having 
   jurisdiction. The parties shall have the right to discovery in accordance with Code of Civil 
   Procedure 1283.05. (2) EXCLUSIONS FROM MEDIATION AND ARBITRATION: The 
   following matters are excluded from mediation and arbitration: (i) a judicial or nonjudicial 
   foreclosure or other action or proceeding to enforce a deed of trust, mortgage, or 
   installment land sale contract as defined in Civil Code 2985; (ii) an unlawful detainer 
   action; (iii) the filing or enforcement of a mechanic's lien; (iv) any matter that is within the 
   jurisdiction of a probate, small claims, or bankruptcy court; and (v) an action for bodily 
   injury or wrongful death or any right of action to which Code of Civil Procedure 337.1 or 
   337.15 applies. The filing of a court action to enable the recording of a notice of pending 
   action, for order of attachment, receivership, injunction, or other provisional remedies, 
   shall not constitute a violation of the mediation and arbitration provisions. (3) Brokers: 
   Lessor and Lessee agree to mediate and arbitrate disputes or claims involving either or 
   both brokers, provided either or both brokers have agreed to such mediation or arbitration 
   prior to, or within a reasonable time after, the dispute or claim is presented to brokers. 
   Any election by either or both brokers to participate in mediation or arbitration shall not 
   result in brokers being deemed parties to the agreement.

   NOTICE: BY INITIALING IN THE SPACE BELOW, YOU ARE AGREEING TO HAVE 
   ANY DISPUTE ARISING OUT OF THE MATTERS INCLUDED IN THE 'ARBITRATION 
   OF DISPUTES' PROVISION DECIDED BY NEUTRAL ARBITRATION AS PROVIDED BY 
   CALIFORNIA LAW AND YOU ARE GIVING UP ANY RIGHTS YOU MIGHT POSSESS 
   TO HAVE THE DISPUTE LITIGATED IN A COURT OR JURY TRIAL. BY INITIALING IN 
   THE SPACE BELOW, YOU ARE GIVING UP YOUR RIGHTS TO DISCOVERY AND



                                              -5-

         APPEAL, UNLESS THOSE RIGHTS ARE SPECIFICALLY INCLUDED IN THE 
         `ARBITRATION OF DISPUTES' PROVISION. IF YOU REFUSE TO SUBMIT TO 
         ARBITRATION AFTER AGREEING TO THIS PROVISION, YOU MAY BE COMPELLED 
         TO ARBITRATE UNDER THE AUTHORITY OF CALIFORNIA CODE OF CIVIL 
         PROCEDURE. YOUR AGREEMENT TO THIS ARBITRATION PROVISION IS 
         VOLUNTARY.

         WE HAVE READ AND UNDERSTAND THE FOREGOING AND AGREE TO SUBMIT 
         DISPUTES ARISING OUT OF MATTERS INCLUDED HE 'ARBITRATION OF 
         DISPUTES' PROVIS TO NEUTRAL ARBITRATI4

         Initials: Lessep:ee._1►,,

9        Premises Condition.
Lessor, at the Lessor's sole cost and expense, shall provide the building in AS-IS condition with 
the following exceptions:

         9.1       All City items not requested to stay during initial walk through shall be removed.

10       Scheduling.
         10.1 The Lessor has all priority rights to use the Premises and will make reasonable 
                   accommodations if a scheduling conflict occurs.

11       Use of City Equipment,
The following City owned items may be used by the Lessee during the schedule hours of 
occupation:

         11.1 Office furnishings

         11.2 Shared areas that include restrooms, copy room, and kitchen/break area.

12       Capital Improvements.
During the entire duration of this agreement, the Lessor will be responsible for major capital 
improvement replacement and major maintenance activities. If specific actions that cause the 
required improvements are directly associated with negligent acts of the Lessee, the Lessee will 
then be responsible for the cost to repair and/or replace the capital projects.

13 Termination.
Either party may terminate this lease upon thirty (30) days written notice to the other party 
pursuant to Section 14 below.

         13.1 After a termination request has been received, a site walk will be performed by 
                   both Parties to determine if the facility is in the same condition as it was in the initial 
                   occupation.

         13.2 Any costs to repair or replace the facility not attributed to Lessor in section 12, will 
                   be paid for by the Lessee through the deposit. Any costs that exceed the deposit 
                   shall be paid by Lessee.




                                                                                                                            -6-

       13.3 If costs of repair are less than the amount of the deposit, the remainder shall be 
             returned to Lessee within 30 days of the final repair invoice payment by Lessor. 
             Should there not be any repair or replacement costs, the full deposit will be 
             returned to the Lessee within thirty (30) days of the final date of occupation.

14 Notices.
All notices, consents, demands and other communications from one party to the other given 
pursuant to the terms of this Lease or under the laws of the State of California, including but not 
limited to notice under the provisions of Section 1161 of the California Code of Civil Procedure 
and Section 1946 of the California Civil Code, shall be in writing and shall be deemed to have 
been fully given when deposited in the United States mail, certified or registered, postage prepaid, 
and addressed to Lessee or Lessor at the addresses respectively specified below or to such other 
place as Lessee or Lessor may from time to time designate by a written notice to the other; or, in 
the case of Lessee, delivered to Lessee at the Premises or at any place where Lessee or any 
agent or employee of Lessee may be found if sent subsequent to Lessee's vacating, deserting, 
abandoning or surrendering of the Premises. Lessee hereby agrees that service of notice in 
accordance with the terms of this Lease shall be in lieu of the methods of service specified in 
Section 1162 of the California Code of Civil Procedure. The provisions of subdivision (a) of 
Section 1013 of the California Code of Civil Procedure, extending the time within which a right 
may be exercised or an act may be done, shall not apply to a notice given pursuant to this Lease.

      The contact information for Lessor is: City of Lemon Grove
                                             3232 Main Street
                                             Lemon Grove, California 91945
                                             Attention: Lydia Romero, City Manager 
                                             Email: Iromerogernongrove.ca.gov 
                                             Phone: 619-825-3800

      The contact information for Lessee is: Home Start
                                             5005 Texas Street, Suite 203
                                             San Diego, CA 92108
                                             Attention: Laura A. Tancredi-Baese 
                                             Email: itancredit-baeseahome-qtart.orq 
                                             Phone: 619-692-0727

Waiver of Relocation Benefits.
Lessee understands it may be entitled to relocation benefits pursuant to Government Code 
section 7260 et seq. In consideration for the terms of this Lease, Lessee knowingly waives any 
right to said relocation benefits pursuant to Civil Code section 3513.


                             SIGNATURES FOLLOW

The Agreement has been executed by the Parties as of the dates set forth below:



Si                                        Signature:

By L                                      By Lessee: Home Start

Printed Name: L dia Romero                Printed Name: Laura A. Tancredi-Baese

Title: City Manager                       Title: Chief Executive Officer 

Signature Date:05 /(                      Signatures Date:  q/171/3-417-°

Attachment A — Site Plan 
  City Hall 
 3232 Main Street

