                      AOREEMENT FOR CONSULTANT SERVICES


       This Agreement for Cons tai Services (Agreernenr) is entered into as of this jid.M 
day of         , 2016, between the City of San Marcos, a diagtofed municipai wrpowinn
(mCIT    and 2-1-1 San Die.9o, a non-Karat corporalion. ("CONSULTANTI tveminafter 
individual 'Party' arid collectively *Parties*.


                                       REOTALS


       WHEREAS, as a recipielrit 0f15deral funds, the City of San Marc'ys is rerpired conduct 
actitialos troll rriee-t the criteria for the naVonal objective of Activties 5ertafitting Low-and 
Moderate-income Persons of the federal Department of liousiog and Urban Development's 
CDB-G Entittement Program, a defined in Title 24 CFR 570.203: and

       WHEREAS, City and Gansuliwt certify that the act:0.11'6es carried out with ti.,ixts provided 
under. this Agreement %JAI meet this CDf3C ram'. National Objective — priricipaity beneit 
loviiinnoderate income persons as defined hr. 24 CFR Part 570.208(a)(2)(A): and

       WHEREAS, Consultant i5 ourreritty pooviding information and referral atssWance fof 
community resourcos and programs. inciuding health and disaster needs to low- and Moderate- 
income residents of San Memos n ,ed of assistance: and

       WHEREAS, h s boon determined to be in this City-1 best internist to reimbursio 
Consultant to ensure the protitslwi of the services are rat curtailed or eliminated: am'

       WHEREAS Consultant states that they are experienced and staffed in a maripar nuch 
that they arc! and con deliver the services requited of City within the time frames Wein provided 
cif acc_ordarice with the terror and conditiono of this Aoreement: and

       WHEREAS, services pr it undo thi4., Agreement will be funded using CMG' tun,ds 
and thus the City and the Consi.Otant must comply with the provisims of Federal regulations 
governing the use of CDBG funds, particularly 24 CFR Part 570.200 to 670.210, 24 CFR Part 
85 'Uniform Adm:nistrabve Requirements for Grants and Cwperative Agreernants to State,
       Srbd Federalty-iecosnized it dian Tribal Governments% 2 CFR 20(.1-- Un:iform 
Adminl.stmtive Requirements, Cost PrinoipleL and A.uclit RequirerneritA for Federal Aotzrels, 
ettlectvc Docember 26, 2014, arid C,DFR 14.218; 34-id

WHEREAS. CITY has ekithortzed preparation of an agreement to retain the services of 
CONSULTANT a hereinafteF set forth..

       NOW, THEREFORE, the Parties Mgr ee fbiiCrWS: 

1,     Scoot cif Work

CONSULTANT will provide services to Cif Y as described in Exhibit 'A entitled "Scope of 
Work" ettachod hereto and lncorporated by reference, CONSULTANT most timely perform the 
Scope of Work in accordance with a schedule approved ty CITY, but in no event Will wily work 
be performed undies- this Agreement Wore the same is executed by both Partiem CiTY most

mtsent trp vrning: to am Mi. to Ste Swim ot Aft, Wirt toch omeentio oft in CITIPS so.% 
dvafAkeri .51:014 "A" vAi iktraMed rookmart foconimat, vAti arty itsiefron tbr which 
arra itatotut heis bee4 tivAtt Any w.,:lOokrie 'TM ft:0o Wvat tvikh arm art 
hes not treen ,•*Akked 144.,  ond v01,

ewe ge.0101aWkfietttiktiri.

OM' OWon vergoie tre: otImbtrte4 =Mt:TAW A linT ACED FE P174408 
fof Fotrertro    2.016-201        rtvWfroannet 1Ut447, tiptolf4d1 47,440*,,,V only ood
fetentiowl CPP, Whim 04-07, SavRegat 0=4M             vm. TAN kg"..Wag 
niiintteubit eggientin 04 -04'ookW We* W Z41 'IliVip=040$ Welfi 0412,0014. 
cfrwrios in own:4246*km and mirteborseratot boyoggi Privvoss 14,t 2015.4n 1 0 sum
witim mintract sinentkree0 0106:" veed aipm by holt Peftiu.          PA* firag Oft s
tea Avioihavoilent prvrion fo4 than* ifte*        pwhiorigp4tont, Sivfrom
docurnerMion         MIAMI kw ri0 ZOOM stihrnited tor RMINVaignort Oot taw ttliciS
fiviuded thIR twoveh        4-; or tWugh ttrInvoti tete% amendatang,          etia4*,), 
ttArtaosomort,

CCNSULTANT woo* SW ti* Control Gott Pmet*go atoS PftWitlweg, 46 CM, Fettvrai 
    Drie4ri r'74ufatiOnS artgra, Cheviot t Pat 3-1L0 eeq, ata tilt mixt tistarmift 
*km-gat d cook kulktexal

Apy onk tot' ithi.dinft oprot h beim. mode 4o 'CONSULTANT itw1/2 am dotzembei 
aottmtherg sudit te koskrositt, ttivAlr 48 CFR, Fottatat MOsiton Recitialtons Splom, 
auttler 1, Part $1,04:4 seq,, pob*,* tavoyeawit by CONWalitii roe CM,

CONSULTAW1 weva to LW CM on a qtartedy '0.644 .3"4:}' amabio Utel,                 mot
Wade a summary of oictok postnrod fafr the pedvi beki       WNW:0W wal samt
kawazow revkvier    Ole wiratkv of Vtty(342). dap ktroMng wnpitgan tit vomit urokgr
ikoratinunt        abutted VW 80 days may Eg4 atft-144 vtljecken ks         soht 
dtomlom kpolgem lhe to, Traria to awe Cantramt Ardramobirotze trot- frAtmliv Odom:


                                   COI Un !Ames 
                              At CMG Prageigrr,, Viatugaf 
                                   1 CtOo Ce-ntot Crbe 
                               .Akri Maims CA 921A1.-2218


& etrifaMMIEVIIII
Thb isomminge. *WI go %Ito tibiet OiN           toottivent von eppromai 4 (AV *el-a
CONSULTMM CONSULTANT gh42 ete4M-Alm WA OW rAfikAtor* rgoxim4 home's 
COMO. Afthictistar,. rao*Iticat atka co 01x,,n,20:12 4,Alevis extroxied ccrtrect - 
sitendMit, proiftd Otiz*on Ctrt 0*, Apogagoik: biicw, Irstier terrphortion porteirA
  SetATIOn 6 1414 figrunord, betw,

ShltaiM OONSULTANT         wiz* etivomrooseettv sotexia atetheitzAtirm prZAidfo
polftegkm4 stehms        med by t,     6.04i1 tertian vdt witskIverod hey* t465en
Aorit COMOLTANT            ma) ri* and ft a watmiser wiftaf§. sed protoorkomil serv;ren 
tOlerated by the an'.

Any fitlay determined t be occ4Noed by causes beyond the al of CONSULTANT ME be 
feasol fot to granting d extension c4 timoi foe Ote trooletion siJch servtoe..a. Wheel stirch 
delay (moors, CONSULTANTriALW ifvertt-dieeti notify ahe CITY'S Cottingt Maiirtistratar iro 
witrig of the cause and the Mdelli of the diAai, whemupon the arcs Contsd AdrntnistMter
    sfiGedmin tiva facts taltd the mdard of the dray and Tani an extension of time for The 
oemptatiort e the profemilianat arc whim, in Ns or hor pitt merit Ns or r *Ones of fad 
lentil,/ sue an •extemion atams The CUTS CoinVact MmInietrolor *tang of fatt vat be fbial 
aroi panes at to tta Partiec This is not Wended depdve CONSULTANT of it$ 100 
ramtdiat in the tvwt of a dispute.

4.

Th. CITYT orOort exteml kvkv           rnoreinent of two yeeTs f a tot4 at Aim yeses iwituld the
tookado ri -a! the Intdal Tom of Agreement as stakel Scation 3, above, not to exceed Vim date 
Of June 30. 419, purawt           ibit "'Swim of Work,4' Unloss erTY notifies CONSULTANT
     :wrtiirs riot toss then a0 ix';y$ prior to the expiralko' dat east CITY doeS. n Intand to renew 
thot ca tract, the cotqatzt   autvan,JA,tteRy be renewed tf    twe-year' Wm,

6. ratAllf.aen
Time of the esseme vvith regfrecl to the orgliotiona ga4 each Platy kindieRf thts Agnaemont. 

         tiLsitattion

This Apterne* troy be temrtirale4 with or MOW MSS by CITY_ Terrrt Othout cause 
c.ra be etreotNe only u    15-day writlen Mititet to MNSULTANT. Outing sNisti 16-day perms
CONSULTANT Me congr                 rfOcr s milwitiog teivim in acconiantx with 
.get!, afer which V.TY vat pay CONSULTANT f Matkonfiible oasts awl monfroxf 
,rtetgrettf Mar io reocipt ef the tegintnation neitm. This Agreetnerit tmy be terminated by VII
for 4--awe in -the event of aq cf the !awing: (I) a matztriel breach fit Awsmont bY
CONSULTANT' (K) rrilvoprovsitatkm by CONSULTANT irt comecZion vAth                           thie 
Agmemml rVftkie metormeoceo lAtivites; midi& (E) CONSULTANT/9 fseiDAre to pixfoon 
5.,K4eioros. under this Aareornomt ea &Wed by WY. Tormirtation far cause AN be effective 
hmedieety upon tho dekvery of written notice of torminakkin to COWLLTANT, ear Mich 
CRY wpay CONSULTANT for its reasponeble costs end OY,perists Kepored pfier to, receipt 
Ole t,ffnhIgion rbobce.

7.     21#9.1§..eacIADS1119115,ifiliamsit
Mass aftealoo     veined In Extikii -A.' CONSULTANT w peovide h own OM Sp a*9 find 
       414-kport ih u)ie. izost aftd onvEnte.

                     Reitoitibie

CITY may to lime to tilme commolicate tv CONSULTANT outahn 'entorinativrk to ambit 
CONSULTAW to ~,iviety Reim Me savices. CZNSULTANT must treat WI Si.W1 
itotorirration ea mralkleatisi, ftether ur rtok so kkottkort and Irma rid disdrzne any patit thereuf 
without thea piof wirldep mnserO of MY. CONSULTANT mod Writ tix$ use arid itirculaVen of 
watt irtformalloi, wen        ita ovtIn oroarizeDri, to the LeAtiont necswery portorm Ike 
serv1405_ The tangoing olipigation or tat SeCtiten 8, SafvetWer, w not arirn any pati, of the

 intorinistOn    (1) h been disclosed pvbitely avaitabie sources of 41.taurvation:. (.114, thro%igh
410 livolt of CONSULTANT, t*Nafitr-rtiselmxi pub4cly ayMable soomes -MiceriasiteA; (ti) 
 now h the posne,AtiontbfiX)NSULIANT without anycb'kcp.tNon ofimfideritairgy; or 
botti)      htgezItor lightivity di..elesetd % CONSUCTANT by a Vtlfd party. tot on$ Me extent
itat the me dieft-isvre tharrwsi Vas berm (-A it; CliaWtAly auftbortzegi by that tad pwty,. 
CONSULTANT mut not disdoso. oby ecerports. reommiocivtiont.               ukr r otheT rts41.11t-% of 
the v.,Prioes ot the existerwe le zobjeci rowdier of Mks Agomilmnt without the Ocr
,,,,onsertt el           perforrnerim herourdw, CONSULTANT w tornt...4y with aleval
obigations nutty now at h            tlaq,.ve osspecting  infirtmlbort or citho. prop rty of Setif 
Othiat Vat'Unit, firm or corporation,


       ekiwg, cettrmirri of thinement, CONSULTANT trtuAZ retion any rzttfidential
             ihitgon was provided by CITY, on tie emr&Z v,och infcimarion i a fonwit        make$ 
  fesebie to mum to CITY.


9„      gp-rsrarlbtlairsgt       .41.,...itigettim


CONSULTANT ti*clares that R.h wat onwkiyea4c             ahod any oompvly o peczor, ether
them a bona We employee WUkires foc CONVATANT, odi tra or SectrIft this tvivenwt that
  ive3 nat. paki cragreetd t tilw arty =Iva% or mug% Ow *xi a et-sa fitte ortIptup*, two./ 
fthe, wrniriiisstm, pomentage, 11(0k-wage, fft, gift or ority c#Mr wrigaidzratkwi, =rdirig50. u.porl or 
rimuking from the wtto.rd of rimiatig Of the Agir,enont. For breach. of Vakallon ttels wry, 
CITY $ the right, b not         obrigation, to wigui    Aptarteri wit !WNW, 00- at it# sae 
discratir" dotict from tha AG-m:44.31mA prim a cartsidavtion, otfustwin wttver The
*mount of stfich knik -cornraimalori, pementage, bcokorege fse,    o cantingvAt t.


10, Ovvejahle,21 Docittruint*


    Inarnomda, iiwcgts, pi, Apezifkziione,            ad other du ment por-peAxi orobteskoo,1
under tto tertnA Ws Agreement *0 be The property 01 WY -!...X,14-SUL1 ATIT mrs.t wow* 
provide gqxtl. dovisreattOm ti.3 CITY iofo6,-rortic. dir 4,01til from* as diretormined by MY. 
Is)theWait of any ru         iageoatiort of the documentz, vut-'41 te-taS c‘fr aaaeraftl bre the 
reeponsibirdy oil are. UrNiri expirattr, pAriier teffronation fees Avimpasnk COWALTANT 
must irtitifn CITY arty ar4 eqent, diccotent o friMeriats end a coin rma 0101'60 
Which CdONSULTANTtvrre. wed from CITY or proititiczed for CiTY for the imposes of MI 
Agromattifit.


ft      2911itkiPD.MMAPALESIL,tiViti—W-Pirrtaltata#SNM.


During the tetto of tut ftoveosetV, CONSULTANT wet sot w.,,t 06 CONSULTAW ot peeform 
senifess of any kind fro say porson ccwitty Mom irriweAlsoi               coileay vAtti Owati
CITY, CONSULTANT wM at stli time& cum* 'with the tenTio, Ihe                  RefiyAct and the 
foariat 0000 r4 tnterest Orairiagt•=0, CONSULTANT Mt irarnatatzly diziwatify *set nrui will rttlk 
tne otriciol poshion Witutxrom arly my wry :raft corntiv 1-Hrort9             art 
CONSULTANT haa a fMrIciat intelisst as delimit in Govien-rmiard Orvie Sisa;on 67103
COSMTANTMpri'MOnt$ and writa thatft ho& kAtamixige of sny                           :Moves 
which would requim it to d'artuOiy itsel frcrn any matter on whith ATM perfoar) igifvt1-4 tar
Crry.



CONSULTANT must con-Oil veltlA 04 of the mvodi ng riNtifr*VIWAS tfthe .ProaktAiRM0071. Act 
end local ordOono       pscificely. COMM:FAN)" must $e Statement§ of Ecomfritc ki-Ittes.t

with ihe City alerki       manner on forms rel*h CONSULTANTain frm the, City


12- Nit AffitatatatlitYALtillAILWYAMME

141$ithei arq part nor fa of th6. Agreement may be ausitined or subcontracted, except a$ 
oftvgivoiao. owlftitike prvAded het-ein, or to wig GITY, sofe $tarkop, 001,126pft ftt 
*Nara* thereof in ono_ Arty azszNproortt OF ttfttlintniZillj *01004% wit POVNOCIII shttlt 
be void.

when any Waft VOUS' tti4 Agreement tb peeicfrned t)V a afbcorittOtilot or SubtonetAziN, 
CONSULTANT lirtay ambe ragekup or adeevitatirtialvo sorthorge for aoch %fork nOt-40-Imetui 
Ws percent (%) of 8014,14 cost of such mit involool to CONSULTANT by svx,11 
taZoontetctor or sobconsottarat

13- MatitnitardattdiP           I !NUM/Whitt

OONSULTANT mutt mo,grIVOri bttoks, dominants, me ornpky,ffirte firm aftegets, sop:x.111*v 
recorde. cgiV. tae pezeuttNeto to (mots Intxrreti and itio$4 14,1011 nude:444z avatatAa 
at its ogioe st. ro,asonai* times during the term of tbfla Nteemegg and fOs five (8) ritS from 
tho dot* trpai pronatra trU Aoment, for iniveotkin by CITY ospd owiela thorned' rtwzi 
be fygpistvad, pequested,

1 4, g9p#32riajsNL

  sti 'time% during th,g. term c4-INS Alreeinttit, CONSMTANT bo imliepaidett wainctof 
and wit riaq he an wcAoyov, to0411, pednor joint von-Wm- of WY, Exoapt crrY may 
spy lri wrkireg. CONSULTANT has no             agruksed kmaed, acift on WO of 
CITY in alv capooity whstooevw at an aRkKt. CONSULTANT tlaor uttonly, exprimed or 
1410,74 purquaot to Oia Aoreorramt to hind CITY to any otagggon vtemftoover, Cfrf ros
right, but not the utotixiciri, etavitrO GONVATANT         the rut of CCANSULTANT8 
sentime fender,sr6 rIfirfiVAnt.t* Shit NinWrivt, however, erre does oat hays, I'm tight to
the moans by vietttch CONSULTANT eactri- Wishes will tervioes„

16- YilarSaMIPARKEtt PrAtatal

CONSOLTAK wartaN, and ononsiants tOmt CONSULTAN r x46414606 thu mOilts5 41U and 
reamorvm portorn te *micas forked by Me Scope Wo6 tn remogrolan And worker 
ilko ingalriet.

       persiprtre91

CONSULTANT must Ettsqpi quaeod ard oaxtMea Fiertiormel PeriOnll eersifte$ Mitre thi$ 
AgrreOrriatia CONSUL-TAN r$ perS,X1014 must at fteAl comply *MI CrlYS cfn4i
policies then In offact OrTY him the rkillt, but not the eblkiatiort, releeew and lime 
coommet porlormiag wok Wide( tht 14Weetlient. CITY hat the ontestieted td, but nr.n. the 
GNIStim            the rwromi of any parscn(s) assigned by C-ONSULTANT coding oral or 
wriltret? mid= to CONSULTANT to nth Ofecti

       LesescttioingLygt

CONSULTN, and orirsubcontetiovx pertyttnd by C-Fre padsm vyott< isodke
  memeot, OA! perit* CITY alid   fiWorat *04'0 proAting timer* lot the PA),"I. (01w
              vvc..rk pElfefftiOd- toder tUM Agreearstmu-actootie *oft durki9 two tit 
this fio.*6.trAirtt trictudm irka*adk re/ww an 3 dsRy

  •UmemktemittlIg

CONWLTANT reiomsem atui tfockartat- Me that, it has ail Woltos, oterriiis, trAgr...-Ittiont
    approvats of whatover ratuvo wi*tt tiettehy roiloW to wsava 4fg.pogtv4itim. 
VASIL,' AM. foproorb emd. warroaft to MY that COMULTANT -st k4k !sole wnt god 
exwte,. kmip effotA 04 thee thrall *10        thi$ Avoterneot, agy toonto, pegnit 
Approwd oJi*tr leg* tepittisel ftw CONSULTANT* t'off its prateseok

19, regglarijamg,

COMULTAW hereby ai that beetle 1p.s a C'of San Ntsmos.Busies inbuoso and 
maintatki fut torof twti effiNA throughout the Um ilemot
      railvit4 intLisartm.

      20.1 epfaci, 00t4SULTANT mtxt        ti    arak-toir, 0.04 tile mike %On dIzs
Agyogor,/ ttpa **min *ivintwo patties. tr4rm   rilot sdnilmed aotiveittod tht ate:
  CAttnii01 Wt3atirtNt instairoce busineso Atie Om      typ& proMfaci 4414 owtA mve
 Sktaelai potic54~1, -Wing of *A keto Mon szt ond framial tAze of Wactir/ logam 
 10,000-,,,000) (MVO* Vieor bettor the most *wed. Mol,„ lam* Kw RON
wsich stmetoodenkiit be ?IVA by soeh et* itcsotv tweviovit et-M not by me*
amzetis (lib* pamot 4utnidiary oftrottit epittiac

                                          Gmentpa       inciude fommiepwopetailicim,
            proculetskomiSeted %,*.catioro yetin),. :brow] fomi privedy.damv, 
            pemnal *Ay, baviy !rto and hbarkfrirOt MnimiTs.40 liktatt, wri tee parq:-Aod orl 
            Apo  o            f.Nlith deferme costs mob additton Mel
            Vwrowiil tta ;to crogria4NYMy exaMOn... itlUra 00 oto tZtitdi ttitsideme. 
            =Pam awl tom tm. prokAton opirat. pigsvont of al VP irx ditdocitMe
            ill Ike-_ eV* oamed kuurees Wong tip do so, twfrageoflo4


            L      $1,0;_k,ODEI pew oteron por woormrim
            it,    T2.,0471,014 wital woo* pm:titled',
                    1 ,044,1100 preipely etanwet: bodtly ocaorente.

      i0) egorarakjitt4, Coveloga from todotta, tmned, Maxi am, owfromed 
            VOW**, 74, be provided on ot *pe* ion behair *it 4,04.418 **to oxywibta
            fri *WWII to poky Amy; theArtviti 1110 tkostAitaily evirneert, thot 
            be no vobbitvon oaalcat paymord 0 '4 OR. or dfickwatiblc tn mogAt etttic2 
            mood imaratts kittro to do 4e, iirtiv following mverAgo =wow

            I      I1,000,00( pot pawn For 0440000%,
                   ;1.,00(003 vAvor.Atail aszigkiaitei -COrribeied:
             kx    S.1 ,000,00.5 proparly damage w boergy injury P Doattrieral,

                ,efO:c.,prial L        iVicy Vntrts ofrtot Pas- g. than 4,2,000,0X wribitzikd sin*
                lietB daira         ormai stwevatc.

        (d),   W91.kiiN--.1.17;Prq ,Paritifft, COvetac14 bi4x amotorri$, wordorwe
                stmitory e'Nuiretpents,

Limb rimy be met kt combins'Opri pdmary anti uraftitatescoms iktaty.                   aid
*Id UtititraialatOsA Otiikrio oteem moat OK reqtatimen                   bova; then be strffloieril
umbrellefeness coverage wigged t exceozi the speoified age mrquhtmeills, Iv that 4 
Oral overit vel4 not lomat dekteany in my of the *wawa- rmarements deovibed abowe;
     LtrobraWev*Ass Wistutance leemmtv May apptfed M.ty 01** tbz VirWtt 4ucarartne
   eer-45e rotioiiretneut for a* cme kret deficlieAt. #         !flgoance_Let .e.4s. #10 racy
specifically pewktft oalemist„            NW the podipn t4 the polk         peovidirio bo 
submitivid for CITY'S reVienht tO

        202 gtielt.,,retriD Entiotvemonts must be obtami w the •?All pciicy4040414 010 
fav4i4 fOtlf platittiorm, iht) w       fa w      wig I* tothe sagsbactiort       Qty Attorney;

        (a) 6stivolimmt (Not iltotied for Pmfeationai efors and Ofrissbn tieMty 
               klnitreMet or Mews' Comerattion4 'City of San Maim And Totectexl eott 
               appoirierl Words, ofVocre4, ageTOZ and emptoyee* ere additionuf Wired With 
               r4atePtiO Vti* Staged pivied onti cantrui with City',

               righolatint. Genf U tz CG 2010 i5, CO 203-7 1001 or Ow 
               oquhraf.ent,

        (t)timipik, *Saki, pato lila not twinkle* nor shag it be cancAid mducod 
               evimits, wahotrl tiotrly (80) dare written .notice tt,t tilt City of Sao ttamw.,"'

               atimrt,Covzia, "fim pckli proVides printery tolturve bt. City of San MA-TCrAri., 
               and Wooled fogt uppoirited boarft, *givers, vect*,           empbpyeft, It is. not 
               secondaty or tri tely way mlbordittato to my Other iriUMK4 colowne 
               mairligriegi by City San Mtrcoe

        (e)      ktigsMbArgan.               waive ariy right of moirely ftlay have
               th4 aty of San Mi:vv:iti. end Its       orld           tormatt, officus
               ttm *es boom* prrxmis we make Ow Limy etamage4 afisigm ow. or
                     0Aefoilno tipaudions yotsr work tithe milder mitred lift Oty Sigo 
               Mme:

        20-3 trMit.ThatMODEWSIikataBiEtaleiktM                        trees roonott$ at to Olt
typo,            of iiststmott ovorage to I)* rioairtbAlned by CONSULTANT as ettviroti by tht;
Siuton           w approval af sott 0-10LIVItte by CM, vro ftrtmlit4 tsti Mid 14 not in ttny
roamer ittra or cp.oPPI VatitiV4-4       ehligAtIons akerteim anorned CONSULTAlft
pursuaryt to tiii% Agreement intititOr4, Iwt net      kt, the mtiemnifictithun prmisfon,

        itenrigalalata.

CONSULTANT ova* provirkt crry watt CANCIWIteS inturarmo Arld awrnparlinq 
erftiorserwrts Murmeing the inoworze °neaps described               poagnotri aboica       form 
end (.tinitAt approwe4 by MY, ;Om to Win* any worrk for this Agreement

lb.** fats0e4 potato/1W iotv, CONSULTANT nuta indoso volact: diftad 
tiAtNe4" eitf APO Sgm Mtorda4 giNt (tV . awl alptbiled bgaittt, W00% %oft roti 
  stankywo tOWtv*, 1WTY                                                                                                                                                                       fflom 4rjebst owy e04 at . 
                                        Wig,''                                                            &moo, o3as, etg 0.0.4444; WM** *Om* kftion
  mew.** utopmiW. 0000, 014 out toibmi phy bad iviratormor                                                                                                                                                                                                                       tivri *Tie vsy
  morgrotti_ 'MN my peemis't                                                                                                      kedoiiiro Oath, or pritorly *mos Ift* rogtv Ate, tgt
  portall le, or wekto $:a pabulum,                                                                                                                                  Qmkiarl 02,700),X.A6T, Ifs wo*ttoo, 
:afgerb mosAxmokeitvitk ii*-1.4Affro wiwitettkvaeh Ihe adhAt melteno 4'4,1
  irkzeimarad Pot**, r,e,s0ing toraiod* dok tokt                                                                                                                                                                                      glicomMot of MY trfornate 
  osiook
                                                                -,4•4".:TA r.• .                 •                                            gitIL                            .1147til,'4-4`1=

840Vd Pviimi wfflamoltt                   urlitv Pnivi4 60 WY *sii hso: t4. 4401001* la OwA*,..ao triA$;.4-***MVet                                                        i*ON11416* Piftxt ot ma*                                                                                                                       h t40
-**404P-tim Agmktert .011 Eta to mnbrivrm vot miltrthto V0solti 
Ow law* r41444 Neowil feat** mgot-egt4 r0. roottkvi tit tow *lot COWAXAKI
                                      . • tiovatO dfttt thtt LWW0,00.- itrAad **At old CM aridg eot dA454-01
          poy 0014aULTP,441 kr. My Wm 21,04•*. httettkp, otii ,tieoft ziroatioa ttr 
ogrimWom lirxt latato, or sly Cong-toaivek oroompwaloi digrAvrn Oy *two *'

24 If                                 stif4.414-                                                               !       ili    .):•4        •   '',':1,:174-44-$                                                     $10.,
CONSULTANT volonoft inis1 tiU orarstma                                                                                                                                                 03004061 * MOM/                                                                                        %theittka
laditJA*1 Ot                                                           oplirokki tviewMfotgosk ior prordisif ;dr. timfd ht any c',Pfirtivitos. Per
Use* or itioiTiatfoi dit van* MY                                                                                                                                                           11.4 OgOA 44,:1 tbaottorzi lottOtAttlao tra
oritt4. *MO Arifft 14 pay ,at* Far VA **RA zi *a wt.* ttveg Wow* ta 44* 
litrrit wobt4 ,:r mtvgnaivt mows' ihs ful *malt wth flad% olUv* 4414v 
mrkiewftwl owalklomilan,

                                                                                                          o 

GOVArrA-Will Orsktiso* 00$14 Math WV waft* a aakdkot undo' puLintAy
4.2itt* Om tot                                                                                              Catkintikftt mwg,TANT tino %mow vata Tot. 2„ ..itioAf,
13/456m*                                                                     pod ItrOttie 44444-talffipoolin oJiwworeereWk Datorog4
*ad Skapoomion futo                                                                                         :                     t*iidnotew Olta tow, of -15m §woop tommilitied 
psmtioh tto trvbitiv tvmer., piarwar, *atm cam oc orimaragf, k wit may emrile-
autlormslm 40taeriopt F:E*40-ey                                                                                                                                           dorsoaktoilat                                                                   titly ary Mu*.
%row hal% atit IWO* amstrAftlit tIvx pat                                        aawAftdod, ***Fmk vat mtgAr otheig4,1tOOffit**4 "Of               REkryoget; 6464MA kwe prociatadsbanwt
waft c'eotl tag bewradamuct. =Met Os10*                                                                                                                                                                                                       ;,•r4 sotftal 424** At
1440 wroiftfri MotiWbri                                                                                                               miti*Otrei**44,304 w 446640 Dthigooldot 4x4*
Om yeisw a„vmoptIon                                                                                                                        01014$014 tElej dulatezi It an

'am/WM 14 se mcmotoor mot 1,0 tiattot morivrommom broom*, tame to 
tootkiapad 641wAroter:ONSULTANT Iwoomitay„ laiwarokorat                                                                                                                                                                                                                   Vglitteig tvo.iam
04-'.406061M                              Pao,:                   t:'                            foUteiM:: erd difte 4111 ft*"

.fixreptions to the Specem r Avard Management {MR, mairftatned by the Goland Semboes. 
MmirOWsition io 1)4 dotatrOed by the, foderai government
       caltittntwaNDEARI 

   finaociak statittitgA pef6onak tedvice, or otlw data  inefotmatilw rotaiwe to cars
opEgatioris, to tvo ars deskriated orAitilepOW by are and rrxdo avagaWie to Cie 
CONSULTANT in ornieg to catty oot this mime& will be. Feotectad by COKS-ULTANT from 
mattrivriteri 'OW 60d d is closure. Perrniesitm to dladose irtorrintiort ort one goon, pubilc 
hesilt: g Nrrki cm( rotating the Contract wfli- rpf,A b.o- CONSULTANT to bier 
disclose such ireovrtatitnek or dissorninvle Itv same on Arty other

CONSULTANT will mat carrimant pktlicly to Vre,    0.; any other' vociule tegoi4Jng the wolf act
or CITY'S actions, ca th* s*rito, exoivi to orrs suit CONSULTANT's iravn perwrinei 
inwiteed i    pettonaint-e of 0'4 contract, gt why hsarirkgr. or SIORponse to queziforis from 
  Legisiaktfe cornrnittee,

CnNSLI.TANT       ftei isukt priy neva roleate or publt relation tetrri of any nature,.
whaiscover., twoRlim work fleilINThed tfP eat3 rxwforirod, *older iNs Coot %About prior 
eeview oft contents th45:44,1 by CITY, and recie.A. of CETYZ written peconislion,

27. 011,0140—BROMea
The Parties agree to make a &Vert flued faith atierapt to ge$thino spy claim, ouritrovergy 
Oto,p4a orlelex? ot:4, or Mating to. this Agreement or corocerrAP0 tbe Gq‘ intocwitMorl 
thealof. if a. dispute. arms bt the Pardee OW connot be WIWI Ow ongagiii2 Ca good
     opreliations, the pain wee to riw4fre    disptitr, porstittot. to the foilovting wocedurdie,
6-441.1 Party thot detignate tedthortwil repreoentAve netpOtetP,    dispute, and f-441
rovesentatIve    atom% to Clue the dptitie by, arey rnftirra; within thair eu'thoeitv,

Iftoe it5Faer ter&IMI5 Unresolved etter by (10) dem the Party virt4 reyootife arty fergValifq 
dispute through (ma,..b.inding) amt:, 114 rioet-biriding gtbitmtion proms via provide fkx 
ate 8610C:gtert NArl Parties a a dtsintelested Wed Cori itztchtrator within thitty 00)
tivB Parka c,aniwyt agnte 1273-g3 an vrtiturtor, then Birin oie nuotrol evibiteotorwii be oppakited 
savant Segliort 12V1.6         Cow          Provaclum The gkce of roe arbiZratWn Val be 
in San. taftoCounty. Califesnis.. The arbitrator witi leoltow the atibstaritfree lat,i4 of the 82cokei 
          kiectuttinq irtlkh$ egidemt5: aryl the aitiVettliffi (W„joion will too supported by 
subtiAar6g OVideriat. The eirb t    l hie no power, 4.44thotity prts,it.ft7 to weld any
puroye or exernplaty           Tho award ytit by made volthin (6) n male, 4,1,1 the
prevailing Party AC ergs to an ertwdof mationable attor,"      fina, mnsvirtoint arid eXpffi
warms foes, and any witi WV.% fot serirms randefed to of tor suth Pad* 
binding wboIraticon does rot riecit.ul toiAtteniernL'. fri* cllaput6 1449-Art six <0) months, 64her Party 
ntay athe WO waggon for a determinatkm thd &glut&

nit praising 16 not intargied k1L, nor AN! it be conetried OtArop the Cm wiols for fling 
any ckwirtt Jar action under Goveomea.    ato,40.ns 900, Seq, Thia dOUlte re501)4011
ppzcses is a mortok0 et)rodltion to this tvreoetnent ami bs exhausted as an aiiimintehttivo 
retrgedy prior to either party irtitiOn illigatim By coricutIng this Agreement, you re egreedng 
to 'Ow divuto omoilutiort proons dowritx4 in t fiection, anti ara gives as right% you
      peen to ;two the tiifiptitt latetod Iv a mot or by My Mat

M Nam, P-0240 gm* xtfata-Aat viRlt Rio Avitud ware kJ* !ma kmimilg
     via" thaa geed kl•             Mow thitivaa mg, MAP natbi fete.W.44 
vorantbl appcmm1;1.• wesksx cc What& MetAt &NA N•ommit is lown osw:Vatt
     ekftwoy pAmstettv .fiagea* mkwoiy-too koon *cat u.A, at* 
ifra day et Womakaitita Os *MI* Wu:IPA omg tqattmen MVO VA ikit OWL Ovo 
road Ettiemot arag, Waftn_ FipAw gc-,Y tvA itifttitv oektiaarzac Afeaga 001-1 attPwA,
fitge,  thavo cisolVaz5 oulesmy grrbrimgm e?s, 'lertmr ixOnoii 41 No tikict*t,

                                         Mama
                                      tkoptimgrit
                                 -00to Cooflo Nat
                               $19m Nomm, CRE'wz,* 
                               FolaimiLt     70,85.20

                               OZ:$ fta M00%
                                 44 PArtpie- tboneu 
                                 att CeMN.
                               ZM1 40504 etaMtg atiMa 
                               rstggyft      71443M

                               211 Ua VoteINFO ME *I' Om 0 
                                    ,3,1ets fteatota, 1;01
                               4vo Egx*, Cci122


         ,444,,%Sietttga

 •.;]-0214ULTANT re-440kgis Wtgok *tivawft, ppm em, . -4A OR* Mast, ffik4V4i:Mv
wareitt end aim imam:* plWarRa ;wiz Wawa.,             et*If ro-wh matt* -ovitei%
  411         fiWitgfe* TAM 414-4 VaMaeg 41;464d st# tie.M (6) two eum, Vra age
d *al pwiretat %Aft. etIo Cimbw4, ft? kepolko ter MY flart6 INkfte      155**04,


;-,* aft            Auctramt
114 Ct5Iwk wiy wittaa auftWegg Waits Mega* *AV FRAWAtifiatR.• 
betwalk                          tagod wan. %ma anfi, ectar4r, pikr
breolt-exa, tlaatnim, iwyntagtom WAVal., Watv                  .;otop:. MOIMAS
 ••Npit„   own0 re          famoras.4 walfge, rie  ort rge ear tioArw
tobigam alga Gitittivd airAilft eneg ity Mr-Wr46; wAr4 god             kf,4
Pag*Am Phi, %A/kW atandinsfA g*, -$6 gotemect dizaw              TO Sib rimma



1110144wt eng brygo lo 'Mlle& a 1SAt tfillanp gIVAA rallgt edigi totY IL441i6k 
Mlantafk4S,

